<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: A Missionary Zeal for Human Rights</title>
	<atom:link href="/a-missionary-zeal-for-human-rights/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/a-missionary-zeal-for-human-rights/</link>
	<description>Critical Collaboration on the Middle East, South Asia, and Africa</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 17:51:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: Max Shmookler</title>
		<link>/a-missionary-zeal-for-human-rights/#comment-43217</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Max Shmookler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 20:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1358#comment-43217</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Mr. Boyette,

I&#039;m grateful for your response. Indeed, my post is an exercise in armchair opinionating. While I don&#039;t see how writing from an armchair, in and of itself, invalidates my opinions, I invite you to share any details about your beliefs that you feel I misrepresented, although keep in mind that I drew my observations from the public record (your NYT interview and other available sources).

More important, I think, are my questions about the relationship between the current violence in the Nuba Mountains and the history of Christian missionary work in Sudan. These are questions you did not answer, and I would still be curious to hear your thoughts about this morally complex past out of which Samaritan&#039;s Purse comes.

Numerous people have responded to my post in private, cautioning me that perhaps I concentrated too much on your personal beliefs, and for this, I apologize. But unlike you, I think that, in the grand scheme of things, it is precisely the larger historical ideologies and organizations which create conditions of instability and violence in countries such as Sudan. Human rights advocates such as yourself should not only be aware of this history, but to be clear about the ways in which your own work differs from earlier--and more transparently problematic--interventions, such as the work of Christian Solidarity International. This history of evangelical Christianity in Sudan is not insignificant; it is one of the factors that has led to the very violence you and your colleagues are admirably dedicated to documenting.

If you have the time and inclination, I would be interested to hear your thoughts on these questions.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mr. Boyette,</p>
<p>I&#8217;m grateful for your response. Indeed, my post is an exercise in armchair opinionating. While I don&#8217;t see how writing from an armchair, in and of itself, invalidates my opinions, I invite you to share any details about your beliefs that you feel I misrepresented, although keep in mind that I drew my observations from the public record (your NYT interview and other available sources).</p>
<p>More important, I think, are my questions about the relationship between the current violence in the Nuba Mountains and the history of Christian missionary work in Sudan. These are questions you did not answer, and I would still be curious to hear your thoughts about this morally complex past out of which Samaritan&#8217;s Purse comes.</p>
<p>Numerous people have responded to my post in private, cautioning me that perhaps I concentrated too much on your personal beliefs, and for this, I apologize. But unlike you, I think that, in the grand scheme of things, it is precisely the larger historical ideologies and organizations which create conditions of instability and violence in countries such as Sudan. Human rights advocates such as yourself should not only be aware of this history, but to be clear about the ways in which your own work differs from earlier&#8211;and more transparently problematic&#8211;interventions, such as the work of Christian Solidarity International. This history of evangelical Christianity in Sudan is not insignificant; it is one of the factors that has led to the very violence you and your colleagues are admirably dedicated to documenting.</p>
<p>If you have the time and inclination, I would be interested to hear your thoughts on these questions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ryan Boyette</title>
		<link>/a-missionary-zeal-for-human-rights/#comment-43154</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Boyette]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 19:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1358#comment-43154</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Mr. Shmookler: I wish you would have contacted me before writing this. You based your piece on assumptions about my beliefs, my work and my life.  I have received no email from you asking about the work that I do.  I don&#039;t see how this kind of misinformed armchair &quot;opinionating&quot; is valuable.  

What would be valuable, is writing about what&#039;s happening to the people of Sudan. They&#039;re going through constant bombardment and the burning of their villages.  Thousands of them are being displaced from their homes.

As a result of the current conflict, many students have lost their chance to get an education and contribute to Sudanese Literature in the future.  I wish this would be the motivation behind your writing and not who I am and who HRF gives their award to.  In the grand scheme of things Ryan Boyette, Samaritan&#039;s Purse and HRF are insignificant on a level of importance when compared to the1000s of people that are undergoing great suffering.  

I encourage you to look over our site (www.NubaReports.org) and evaluate some of our video and text reports, that our team of Sudanese journalists, have risked their lives to report.  Thank you.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mr. Shmookler: I wish you would have contacted me before writing this. You based your piece on assumptions about my beliefs, my work and my life.  I have received no email from you asking about the work that I do.  I don&#8217;t see how this kind of misinformed armchair &#8220;opinionating&#8221; is valuable.  </p>
<p>What would be valuable, is writing about what&#8217;s happening to the people of Sudan. They&#8217;re going through constant bombardment and the burning of their villages.  Thousands of them are being displaced from their homes.</p>
<p>As a result of the current conflict, many students have lost their chance to get an education and contribute to Sudanese Literature in the future.  I wish this would be the motivation behind your writing and not who I am and who HRF gives their award to.  In the grand scheme of things Ryan Boyette, Samaritan&#8217;s Purse and HRF are insignificant on a level of importance when compared to the1000s of people that are undergoing great suffering.  </p>
<p>I encourage you to look over our site (www.NubaReports.org) and evaluate some of our video and text reports, that our team of Sudanese journalists, have risked their lives to report.  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Melani McAlister</title>
		<link>/a-missionary-zeal-for-human-rights/#comment-5524</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melani McAlister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 14:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1358#comment-5524</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Great piece! It&#039;s important that Human Rights First and other organizations recognize and speak openly about evangelical involvement in Sudan and elsewhere. It&#039;s not that evangelicals can&#039;t be human rights activists -- they increasingly are. But evangelical involvement in Sudan, and the work of Samaritan&#039;s Purse in particular, has a very complicated history, where bravery and commitment were mixed with politics and policies that encouraged a view of Sudan&#039;s conflicts in religious (Christian-Muslim) terms. Human Rights First does need to acknowledge this history.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Great piece! It&#8217;s important that Human Rights First and other organizations recognize and speak openly about evangelical involvement in Sudan and elsewhere. It&#8217;s not that evangelicals can&#8217;t be human rights activists &#8212; they increasingly are. But evangelical involvement in Sudan, and the work of Samaritan&#8217;s Purse in particular, has a very complicated history, where bravery and commitment were mixed with politics and policies that encouraged a view of Sudan&#8217;s conflicts in religious (Christian-Muslim) terms. Human Rights First does need to acknowledge this history.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
