<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Teaching Notes III: Islamic Studies and &#8220;de-programming&#8221;</title>
	<atom:link href="/teaching-notes-iii/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/teaching-notes-iii/</link>
	<description>Critical Collaboration on the Middle East, South Asia, and Africa</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 17:51:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: Sahar</title>
		<link>/teaching-notes-iii/#comment-475</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sahar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 20:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=872#comment-475</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks Christine. Sometimes these classroom discussions can be difficult, uncomfortable -- even disappointing.  It&#039;s great to hear you had a productive discussion with your students both about the material they were assigned to read as well as the discourse they are most likely hearing outside the classroom which they were able to view critically.  It proves, to me at least, that it is important to make room for flexibility with our class agendas to intelligently respond to these concerns when they come up (which it seems like is what you did!).]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks Christine. Sometimes these classroom discussions can be difficult, uncomfortable &#8212; even disappointing.  It&#8217;s great to hear you had a productive discussion with your students both about the material they were assigned to read as well as the discourse they are most likely hearing outside the classroom which they were able to view critically.  It proves, to me at least, that it is important to make room for flexibility with our class agendas to intelligently respond to these concerns when they come up (which it seems like is what you did!).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Christine</title>
		<link>/teaching-notes-iii/#comment-302</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 13:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=872#comment-302</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Replying to myself because we had a nice long discussion in class this week where we talked about how problematic it was to link events in the life of the Prophet Muhammad with groups like ISIL.  A lot of students passionately decried such facile links and (seriously, without my prompting) compared linking Islam and ISIL with linking Christianity and the KKK.

It made me pretty happy.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Replying to myself because we had a nice long discussion in class this week where we talked about how problematic it was to link events in the life of the Prophet Muhammad with groups like ISIL.  A lot of students passionately decried such facile links and (seriously, without my prompting) compared linking Islam and ISIL with linking Christianity and the KKK.</p>
<p>It made me pretty happy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Christine</title>
		<link>/teaching-notes-iii/#comment-301</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 13:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=872#comment-301</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That&#039;s an excellent reflection -- and I&#039;ve been thinking about similar things this week.  I had my students read a biography of the Prophet (Jonathon Brown&#039;s &quot;A Very Short Introduction to the Prophet Muhammad,&quot; which incorporates a discussion of Ibn Ishaq&#039;s Sira as well as issues of the legacy of the Prophet and his memory).  I asked them to submit discussion questions about the book and I was saddened that so many of the questions were, well, a bit Islamophobic.  Some of the student&#039;s seemed to realize it -- they would preface their questions with statements like &quot;I&#039;m not trying to be biased&quot; or &quot;I&#039;m not trying to cause trouble, but&quot; and then ask questions that were either ahistorical, extraordinarily presentist, or tried to directly link events from the Prophet&#039;s life with, for example, the rise of ISIS/ISIL.  I had a chat with them about what constitutes a &#039;historical&#039; question and about the dangers of presentism overall, but it&#039;s such a difficult thing to deal with.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s an excellent reflection &#8212; and I&#8217;ve been thinking about similar things this week.  I had my students read a biography of the Prophet (Jonathon Brown&#8217;s &#8220;A Very Short Introduction to the Prophet Muhammad,&#8221; which incorporates a discussion of Ibn Ishaq&#8217;s Sira as well as issues of the legacy of the Prophet and his memory).  I asked them to submit discussion questions about the book and I was saddened that so many of the questions were, well, a bit Islamophobic.  Some of the student&#8217;s seemed to realize it &#8212; they would preface their questions with statements like &#8220;I&#8217;m not trying to be biased&#8221; or &#8220;I&#8217;m not trying to cause trouble, but&#8221; and then ask questions that were either ahistorical, extraordinarily presentist, or tried to directly link events from the Prophet&#8217;s life with, for example, the rise of ISIS/ISIL.  I had a chat with them about what constitutes a &#8216;historical&#8217; question and about the dangers of presentism overall, but it&#8217;s such a difficult thing to deal with.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
