<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Between Miracle and Afterthought: Hebrew in MESAAS</title>
	<atom:link href="/between-miracle-and-afterthought-hebrew-in-mesaas/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/between-miracle-and-afterthought-hebrew-in-mesaas/</link>
	<description>Critical Collaboration on the Middle East, South Asia, and Africa</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 17:51:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: David</title>
		<link>/between-miracle-and-afterthought-hebrew-in-mesaas/#comment-1712</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 22:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1159#comment-1712</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In response to Sarah: Do you evaluate every art form in historical or political context? I would argue that any art form should have it&#039;s own life and can definitely be evaluated almost a vacuum.  

Both your comments are severely tainted by your very obvious political views, and are based on quite a few wrong historical assumptions.  One example  can be &quot;as I said, I don’t believe there’s anything that qualifies as structural continuity between pre-19th C usages of Hebrew and the standardized, homogenized Modern Hebrew of Ben Yehuda et al which is a radically different language&quot;  or &quot;As if modern Hebrew was revived by Palestinian Jews and not imposed by white settlers and campaigners through the British Mandate as part of the systematic theft, expulsion, displacement and mass murder of Palestinian Arabs &quot; - both may be great political arguments or intellectual exercises but are factually inaccurate to say the list.

And while you are stating that you &quot;did not wonder whether or not Hebrew should have a right to exist at all&quot; tends to hide a deeper intention of just that.  Saying that &quot;one of my research languages happens to be Hebrew, and I have for years been an avid consumer of Israeli cultural production&quot; sounds very close to &quot;some of my best friends are Jews&quot;.  It seems to me that your arguments (the unsubstantiated ones) tend to hide mostly a political agenda. Good Luck.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In response to Sarah: Do you evaluate every art form in historical or political context? I would argue that any art form should have it&#8217;s own life and can definitely be evaluated almost a vacuum.  </p>
<p>Both your comments are severely tainted by your very obvious political views, and are based on quite a few wrong historical assumptions.  One example  can be &#8220;as I said, I don’t believe there’s anything that qualifies as structural continuity between pre-19th C usages of Hebrew and the standardized, homogenized Modern Hebrew of Ben Yehuda et al which is a radically different language&#8221;  or &#8220;As if modern Hebrew was revived by Palestinian Jews and not imposed by white settlers and campaigners through the British Mandate as part of the systematic theft, expulsion, displacement and mass murder of Palestinian Arabs &#8221; &#8211; both may be great political arguments or intellectual exercises but are factually inaccurate to say the list.</p>
<p>And while you are stating that you &#8220;did not wonder whether or not Hebrew should have a right to exist at all&#8221; tends to hide a deeper intention of just that.  Saying that &#8220;one of my research languages happens to be Hebrew, and I have for years been an avid consumer of Israeli cultural production&#8221; sounds very close to &#8220;some of my best friends are Jews&#8221;.  It seems to me that your arguments (the unsubstantiated ones) tend to hide mostly a political agenda. Good Luck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Sarah</title>
		<link>/between-miracle-and-afterthought-hebrew-in-mesaas/#comment-1277</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 23:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1159#comment-1277</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In response to Aviv Becher&#039;s statement that &quot;Hebrew literature and Israeli culture fits into MESAAS geographically;&quot;, this is what I said:

&quot;I’m not sure that the American war machine that is the Jewish supremacist outpost called ‘Israel’ needs to have any kind of geographical or linguistic place – nevermind an equivocated one – in MESAAS or elsewhere. The best service that can be done to Hebrew as a language is to disaggregate its pre-modern archives entirely from its modern and contemporary usurpers. Good luck.&quot; 

I did not wonder &quot;whether or not Hebrew should have a right to exist at all.&quot; (I have no clue what a &quot;right to exist&quot; is, nor how it can be given/withdrawn or by what particular agent in this idiom) nor did I suggest that the study of Hebrew or Hebrew literature of any variety should not be conducted in MESAAS. I said that &quot;Israel&quot; and &quot;Israeli culture&quot; need not be normalized as such in order for these studies to be carried out (one of my research languages happens to be Hebrew, and I have for years been an avid consumer of Israeli cultural production). The project Aviv Becher gestured towards and which I caution against, is precisely the project of treating modern Hebrew as an ahistorical language continuous with pre-Zionist cultural production, and of treating  the undifferentiated category of &quot;Israeli&quot; writers as ones who &quot;belong geographically&quot; in MESAAS. What I am suggesting is precisely that those who study modern Hebrew language and literature do so critically and not normatively. That begins by recognizing the historical specificity of modern Hebrew and its political status -- not searching for continuity by collapsing politics altogether.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In response to Aviv Becher&#8217;s statement that &#8220;Hebrew literature and Israeli culture fits into MESAAS geographically;&#8221;, this is what I said:</p>
<p>&#8220;I’m not sure that the American war machine that is the Jewish supremacist outpost called ‘Israel’ needs to have any kind of geographical or linguistic place – nevermind an equivocated one – in MESAAS or elsewhere. The best service that can be done to Hebrew as a language is to disaggregate its pre-modern archives entirely from its modern and contemporary usurpers. Good luck.&#8221; </p>
<p>I did not wonder &#8220;whether or not Hebrew should have a right to exist at all.&#8221; (I have no clue what a &#8220;right to exist&#8221; is, nor how it can be given/withdrawn or by what particular agent in this idiom) nor did I suggest that the study of Hebrew or Hebrew literature of any variety should not be conducted in MESAAS. I said that &#8220;Israel&#8221; and &#8220;Israeli culture&#8221; need not be normalized as such in order for these studies to be carried out (one of my research languages happens to be Hebrew, and I have for years been an avid consumer of Israeli cultural production). The project Aviv Becher gestured towards and which I caution against, is precisely the project of treating modern Hebrew as an ahistorical language continuous with pre-Zionist cultural production, and of treating  the undifferentiated category of &#8220;Israeli&#8221; writers as ones who &#8220;belong geographically&#8221; in MESAAS. What I am suggesting is precisely that those who study modern Hebrew language and literature do so critically and not normatively. That begins by recognizing the historical specificity of modern Hebrew and its political status &#8212; not searching for continuity by collapsing politics altogether.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Aviv Becher</title>
		<link>/between-miracle-and-afterthought-hebrew-in-mesaas/#comment-1213</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aviv Becher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 15:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1159#comment-1213</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I appreciate these comments and reflections, especially for the ways in which a central concern of mine has become increasingly evident: did I lose the right to read Hebrew literature because Modern Hebrew language is uniquely &quot;directly tied to the character of settler-colonialism&quot; ? Does everyone who reads Hebrew literature support a nationalist and settler colonial project that continues to accept and internalize European antisemitism? The answer to both these questions is, of course, &quot;no&quot;. Modern Hebrew literature does exist.  It is not always political and does not always need to be read for its politics. Hebrew literature is worthy of literary-scholarly and critical-political attention alike. The two are not mutually exclusive. 

The comments to this piece focus almost entirely on the dangers of treating Modern Hebrew literature as any other MESAAS language. These messages of caution culminate in Sarah&#039;s wondering whether or not Hebrew should have a right to exist at all. I suggest we consider that training scholars of Hebrew literature in departments like MESAAS ensures that studies of contemporary Hebrew literature will not lose sight of Hebrew language&#039;s revival process nor of this process&#039; political status. Not training scholars of Hebrew literature at all, because Hebrew language and its Israeli context is a Jewish supremacist outpost for the American war machine, or directing these scholars to more insular departments of Jewish Studies, both neglects political issues that need attention and potentially rejects the very life of a language, its authors and its readers.  There must be room to study Hebrew literature. Where else does study of modern Hebrew literature belong?]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I appreciate these comments and reflections, especially for the ways in which a central concern of mine has become increasingly evident: did I lose the right to read Hebrew literature because Modern Hebrew language is uniquely &#8220;directly tied to the character of settler-colonialism&#8221; ? Does everyone who reads Hebrew literature support a nationalist and settler colonial project that continues to accept and internalize European antisemitism? The answer to both these questions is, of course, &#8220;no&#8221;. Modern Hebrew literature does exist.  It is not always political and does not always need to be read for its politics. Hebrew literature is worthy of literary-scholarly and critical-political attention alike. The two are not mutually exclusive. </p>
<p>The comments to this piece focus almost entirely on the dangers of treating Modern Hebrew literature as any other MESAAS language. These messages of caution culminate in Sarah&#8217;s wondering whether or not Hebrew should have a right to exist at all. I suggest we consider that training scholars of Hebrew literature in departments like MESAAS ensures that studies of contemporary Hebrew literature will not lose sight of Hebrew language&#8217;s revival process nor of this process&#8217; political status. Not training scholars of Hebrew literature at all, because Hebrew language and its Israeli context is a Jewish supremacist outpost for the American war machine, or directing these scholars to more insular departments of Jewish Studies, both neglects political issues that need attention and potentially rejects the very life of a language, its authors and its readers.  There must be room to study Hebrew literature. Where else does study of modern Hebrew literature belong?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Sarah</title>
		<link>/between-miracle-and-afterthought-hebrew-in-mesaas/#comment-668</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 03:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1159#comment-668</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since I was asked to comment: I have a handful of serious reservations about the equivocating, if not normalizing, tenor regarding &quot;Israel&quot; and its related cultural production in this post, but let me set these aside for a second. Aviv Becher raises some good points, but it&#039;s not clear what the alternative archives are that she&#039;s drawing on (or which Max Shmookler refers to) in her argument about continuity between modern Hebrew and pre-Zionist linguistic practices (for one thing I can confidently argue that any pre-19 C century usage differed substantially between European and non-European contexts; between religious and non-religious communities; was sometimes the object of hostility by assimilationists in Western Europe and elsewhere; was grammatically, lexically and syntactically of a substantially different nature, etc). In the absence of a more elaborated genealogy that accounts for this world-scale variety and difference, I have to echo the first comment in this thread. Modern Hebrew was and remains attenuated to a European nationalist and settler colonial project that accepted and internalized European antisemitism; I&#039;m not sure how it can be otherwise as long as this project remains intact. The very idea of proposing a unified and dehistoricized &quot;Hebrew literature&quot; prior to the nineteenth century is a political statement  because as far as I know, whatever Hebrew was used up to the eighteenth century was used for religious reasons or perhaps for highly specific and circumscribed cultural projects. It wasn&#039;t the standardized European language of modern Hebrew. It would be interesting to read an intellectual history that provincializes Ben Yehuda and other political Zionists who led the production of modern Hebrew by shedding light on other visions and practices whether in Europe or elsewhere, but in both cases the historical specificity of these practices would have to be cautiously foregrounded within their own local contexts and not interpellated to some overarching linguistic umbrella. That intellectual history (or linguistic history) would be interesting. But that is all it would be. By contrast, collapsing history itself and diluting both linguistic and archival difference through the projection of a singular &quot;Hebrew&quot; simply reproduces Zionist narratives about continuity, and as we all know (I think...), these are deeply racialized narratives. Likewise, I don&#039;t agree with Max Shmookler&#039;s comparison of Hebrew and Arabic or even Hebrew and Turkish, first on linguistic grounds (as I said, I don&#039;t believe there&#039;s anything that qualifies as structural continuity between pre-19th C usages of Hebrew and the standardized, homogenized Modern Hebrew of Ben Yehuda et al which is a radically different language), and second and perhaps most importantly, on political grounds. Comparing Zionism to other nationalisms - however racist and genocidal, by degrees, they have been - is a common red herring among its proponents. As if modern Hebrew was revived by Palestinian Jews and not imposed by white settlers and campaigners through the British Mandate as part of the systematic theft, expulsion, displacement and mass murder of Palestinian Arabs -- what Max Shmookler glosses as the &quot;political violence behind Zionism&quot; . The centrality of modern Hebrew to the Zionist project is worlds apart from the relationship between any other modern language and the imaginaries of development and nationalism that accompanied it, including the Turkish case. There is also the somewhat pertinent fact that &quot;the violence behind Zionism&quot; which is really the violence OF Zionism, is a violence still ongoing as we speak. I&#039;m not sure that the American war machine that is the Jewish supremacist outpost called &#039;Israel&#039; needs to have any kind of geographical or linguistic place - nevermind an equivocated one - in MESAAS or elsewhere. The best service that can be done to Hebrew as a language is to disaggregate its pre-modern archives entirely from its modern and contemporary usurpers. Good luck.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since I was asked to comment: I have a handful of serious reservations about the equivocating, if not normalizing, tenor regarding &#8220;Israel&#8221; and its related cultural production in this post, but let me set these aside for a second. Aviv Becher raises some good points, but it&#8217;s not clear what the alternative archives are that she&#8217;s drawing on (or which Max Shmookler refers to) in her argument about continuity between modern Hebrew and pre-Zionist linguistic practices (for one thing I can confidently argue that any pre-19 C century usage differed substantially between European and non-European contexts; between religious and non-religious communities; was sometimes the object of hostility by assimilationists in Western Europe and elsewhere; was grammatically, lexically and syntactically of a substantially different nature, etc). In the absence of a more elaborated genealogy that accounts for this world-scale variety and difference, I have to echo the first comment in this thread. Modern Hebrew was and remains attenuated to a European nationalist and settler colonial project that accepted and internalized European antisemitism; I&#8217;m not sure how it can be otherwise as long as this project remains intact. The very idea of proposing a unified and dehistoricized &#8220;Hebrew literature&#8221; prior to the nineteenth century is a political statement  because as far as I know, whatever Hebrew was used up to the eighteenth century was used for religious reasons or perhaps for highly specific and circumscribed cultural projects. It wasn&#8217;t the standardized European language of modern Hebrew. It would be interesting to read an intellectual history that provincializes Ben Yehuda and other political Zionists who led the production of modern Hebrew by shedding light on other visions and practices whether in Europe or elsewhere, but in both cases the historical specificity of these practices would have to be cautiously foregrounded within their own local contexts and not interpellated to some overarching linguistic umbrella. That intellectual history (or linguistic history) would be interesting. But that is all it would be. By contrast, collapsing history itself and diluting both linguistic and archival difference through the projection of a singular &#8220;Hebrew&#8221; simply reproduces Zionist narratives about continuity, and as we all know (I think&#8230;), these are deeply racialized narratives. Likewise, I don&#8217;t agree with Max Shmookler&#8217;s comparison of Hebrew and Arabic or even Hebrew and Turkish, first on linguistic grounds (as I said, I don&#8217;t believe there&#8217;s anything that qualifies as structural continuity between pre-19th C usages of Hebrew and the standardized, homogenized Modern Hebrew of Ben Yehuda et al which is a radically different language), and second and perhaps most importantly, on political grounds. Comparing Zionism to other nationalisms &#8211; however racist and genocidal, by degrees, they have been &#8211; is a common red herring among its proponents. As if modern Hebrew was revived by Palestinian Jews and not imposed by white settlers and campaigners through the British Mandate as part of the systematic theft, expulsion, displacement and mass murder of Palestinian Arabs &#8212; what Max Shmookler glosses as the &#8220;political violence behind Zionism&#8221; . The centrality of modern Hebrew to the Zionist project is worlds apart from the relationship between any other modern language and the imaginaries of development and nationalism that accompanied it, including the Turkish case. There is also the somewhat pertinent fact that &#8220;the violence behind Zionism&#8221; which is really the violence OF Zionism, is a violence still ongoing as we speak. I&#8217;m not sure that the American war machine that is the Jewish supremacist outpost called &#8216;Israel&#8217; needs to have any kind of geographical or linguistic place &#8211; nevermind an equivocated one &#8211; in MESAAS or elsewhere. The best service that can be done to Hebrew as a language is to disaggregate its pre-modern archives entirely from its modern and contemporary usurpers. Good luck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: "Geography" is not innocent</title>
		<link>/between-miracle-and-afterthought-hebrew-in-mesaas/#comment-582</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA["Geography" is not innocent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 16:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1159#comment-582</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A language is not &quot;racist&quot;, people and their political movements and systems are. The issue at stake is not comparative genealogies of genocide but of the political status of modern linguistic revivals. It&#039;s a somewhat banal and easily acknowledged point that the nation-state involves to varying degrees the construction of national subjects and that central to this hegemony is the positive place and modification of language - Turkey  and the construction of the Turk being just one more salient example in the region. My response was to Aviv Becher&#039;s question about the difference specific to Hebrew; I&#039;m arguing that this difference is directly tied to the character of settler-colonialism (that is, settler-capitalism); generalizing &#039;the political violence&#039; behind modern national languages to cover the violence specific to modern Hebrew (a violence that affected Jews before it affected Palestinians) is disingenuous. Hebrew revival, both in its animating motives and its cumulative effects, was of a transformative European and anti-semitic character. This is not a question of scholasticism but of critical political attention; if you read Zionist thinkers even much earlier than the conventional markers of &#039;political Zionism&#039; (qua Harzl, Jabotinsky, etc) and including those invested in &#039;cultural Zionism&#039; including its liberal variants, you&#039;ll find them speaking in transformative and culturalist rather than restorative or traditionalist terms.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A language is not &#8220;racist&#8221;, people and their political movements and systems are. The issue at stake is not comparative genealogies of genocide but of the political status of modern linguistic revivals. It&#8217;s a somewhat banal and easily acknowledged point that the nation-state involves to varying degrees the construction of national subjects and that central to this hegemony is the positive place and modification of language &#8211; Turkey  and the construction of the Turk being just one more salient example in the region. My response was to Aviv Becher&#8217;s question about the difference specific to Hebrew; I&#8217;m arguing that this difference is directly tied to the character of settler-colonialism (that is, settler-capitalism); generalizing &#8216;the political violence&#8217; behind modern national languages to cover the violence specific to modern Hebrew (a violence that affected Jews before it affected Palestinians) is disingenuous. Hebrew revival, both in its animating motives and its cumulative effects, was of a transformative European and anti-semitic character. This is not a question of scholasticism but of critical political attention; if you read Zionist thinkers even much earlier than the conventional markers of &#8216;political Zionism&#8217; (qua Harzl, Jabotinsky, etc) and including those invested in &#8216;cultural Zionism&#8217; including its liberal variants, you&#8217;ll find them speaking in transformative and culturalist rather than restorative or traditionalist terms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
