<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments for Baraza</title>
	<atom:link href="/comments/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Critical Collaboration on the Middle East, South Asia, and Africa</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 17:51:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Persian, Indo-Persian, and Homeless Texts by milind</title>
		<link>/indopersianhomelesstexts/#comment-212313</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[milind]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 17:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://barazaonline.wordpress.com/?p=274#comment-212313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Farsi language never grew roots among common masses.  Many non-Muslims learned the language to secure administrative position and career advancement.  Despite it being patronized as the language of high culture for centuries, it is not a surprise that it has vanished from the subcontinent.  

There is a huge repository of documents in Hyderabad (India) in Indian Farsi, poorly maintained and may be a great source of history.  I have been told that modern Farsi is much different that this Farsi.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Farsi language never grew roots among common masses.  Many non-Muslims learned the language to secure administrative position and career advancement.  Despite it being patronized as the language of high culture for centuries, it is not a surprise that it has vanished from the subcontinent.  </p>
<p>There is a huge repository of documents in Hyderabad (India) in Indian Farsi, poorly maintained and may be a great source of history.  I have been told that modern Farsi is much different that this Farsi.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Antonio de Sosa’s Moors/Moros in &#8216;Topography of Algiers&#8217; by Dana Marniche</title>
		<link>/antonio-de-sosas-moorsmoros-in-topography-of-algiers/#comment-211020</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dana Marniche]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 14:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://barazaonline.wordpress.com/?p=628#comment-211020</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thank you for your well researched article. Interesting information with regard to the change in usage of the words Moors, Arabs, Berbers, etc. by a Portuguese individual in that period.  Remarkable that   he mentions the people later European colonialist painters refer to as &quot;Arabian&quot; or &quot;Arab bedouin&quot; as the &quot;Moors&quot; that in particular conquered Spain.  

Also to be noted is where Sosa maintains the formerly Christian renegades outnumbered the other  Muslims, Turks and Jews in Algiers.  Correlates  with the mention by Robert Brown in his translation of  History and Description of Africa by Leo Africanus of the &quot;endless&quot; number of Europeans turned Muslim or renegade that had come and were present in the Maghreb in general.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thank you for your well researched article. Interesting information with regard to the change in usage of the words Moors, Arabs, Berbers, etc. by a Portuguese individual in that period.  Remarkable that   he mentions the people later European colonialist painters refer to as &#8220;Arabian&#8221; or &#8220;Arab bedouin&#8221; as the &#8220;Moors&#8221; that in particular conquered Spain.  </p>
<p>Also to be noted is where Sosa maintains the formerly Christian renegades outnumbered the other  Muslims, Turks and Jews in Algiers.  Correlates  with the mention by Robert Brown in his translation of  History and Description of Africa by Leo Africanus of the &#8220;endless&#8221; number of Europeans turned Muslim or renegade that had come and were present in the Maghreb in general.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Tariq Ramadan&#8217;s Burden by ACT.ID</title>
		<link>/tariq-ramadans-burden/#comment-205242</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ACT.ID]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 02:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=863#comment-205242</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Marhaban Ya Ramadhan, in this blessed month let us meet with religious practices and social practices to more generous]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marhaban Ya Ramadhan, in this blessed month let us meet with religious practices and social practices to more generous</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Teaching to Learn by Jonathan Potter</title>
		<link>/teaching-to-learn/#comment-205232</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Potter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 12:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1611#comment-205232</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am looking for help with a single word. With your Sudanese translation experience (or connections) might you help? I heard it from local people near the Jebel Marra  in 1981. Its not an Arabic word I know so may be a Darfuri dialect? 

Its (as I remember it anyway) TIGL and refers to an animal.

Any light you can shine would be much appreciated.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am looking for help with a single word. With your Sudanese translation experience (or connections) might you help? I heard it from local people near the Jebel Marra  in 1981. Its not an Arabic word I know so may be a Darfuri dialect? </p>
<p>Its (as I remember it anyway) TIGL and refers to an animal.</p>
<p>Any light you can shine would be much appreciated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Comment on Protests in India: Who Will be the Final Victim of this Anger? by Aditya</title>
		<link>/protests-in-india/#comment-201292</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aditya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 10:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://barazaonline.wordpress.com/?p=179#comment-201292</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lakshmi, 

Found your article quite interesting, and your thoughts mature and very insightful. The observation of the paradoxical roles of B. R. Ambekar and M. K. Gandhi was especially interesting. The topic of this article is a very touchy one, and you have kept that in mind, so well done. Must have required courage and careful consideration. I think you will find this interesting:

http://isha.sadhguru.org/blog/sadhguru/spot/no-such-thing-justice/

Keep writing


-Aditya]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lakshmi, </p>
<p>Found your article quite interesting, and your thoughts mature and very insightful. The observation of the paradoxical roles of B. R. Ambekar and M. K. Gandhi was especially interesting. The topic of this article is a very touchy one, and you have kept that in mind, so well done. Must have required courage and careful consideration. I think you will find this interesting:</p>
<p><a href="http://isha.sadhguru.org/blog/sadhguru/spot/no-such-thing-justice/" rel="nofollow">http://isha.sadhguru.org/blog/sadhguru/spot/no-such-thing-justice/</a></p>
<p>Keep writing</p>
<p>-Aditya</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
