<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Antonio de Sosa’s Moors/Moros in &#8216;Topography of Algiers&#8217;</title>
	<atom:link href="/antonio-de-sosas-moorsmoros-in-topography-of-algiers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/antonio-de-sosas-moorsmoros-in-topography-of-algiers/</link>
	<description>Critical Collaboration on the Middle East, South Asia, and Africa</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 17:51:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>By: Dana Marniche</title>
		<link>/antonio-de-sosas-moorsmoros-in-topography-of-algiers/#comment-211020</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dana Marniche]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 14:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://barazaonline.wordpress.com/?p=628#comment-211020</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thank you for your well researched article. Interesting information with regard to the change in usage of the words Moors, Arabs, Berbers, etc. by a Portuguese individual in that period.  Remarkable that   he mentions the people later European colonialist painters refer to as &quot;Arabian&quot; or &quot;Arab bedouin&quot; as the &quot;Moors&quot; that in particular conquered Spain.  

Also to be noted is where Sosa maintains the formerly Christian renegades outnumbered the other  Muslims, Turks and Jews in Algiers.  Correlates  with the mention by Robert Brown in his translation of  History and Description of Africa by Leo Africanus of the &quot;endless&quot; number of Europeans turned Muslim or renegade that had come and were present in the Maghreb in general.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thank you for your well researched article. Interesting information with regard to the change in usage of the words Moors, Arabs, Berbers, etc. by a Portuguese individual in that period.  Remarkable that   he mentions the people later European colonialist painters refer to as &#8220;Arabian&#8221; or &#8220;Arab bedouin&#8221; as the &#8220;Moors&#8221; that in particular conquered Spain.  </p>
<p>Also to be noted is where Sosa maintains the formerly Christian renegades outnumbered the other  Muslims, Turks and Jews in Algiers.  Correlates  with the mention by Robert Brown in his translation of  History and Description of Africa by Leo Africanus of the &#8220;endless&#8221; number of Europeans turned Muslim or renegade that had come and were present in the Maghreb in general.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
